Michael Phan

3368 Altadena Avenue, San Diego, CA 92105 | M: (619) 940-9229 | michaelphan21@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Highly-motivated individual with a diverse skill set and 3 years of workforce experience with developing and designing robust code for software programs. Enthusiastic and supportive with a willingness to learn and take ownership of core responsibilities while mentoring others. Interested in a challenging career that will allow me to grow personally and professionally.

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

Programming Experience (1 - 10):

- Proficient (6.5): C/C++, Java, SQL
- Intermediate (5): HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, XML, AJAX, COBOL

Other Experience and Tools:

Strong Work Ethic

- Agile/Scrum methodology
- BitBucket & Git NetBeans & MS Visual Studio

Adaptability

AIX & UNIX Command Line

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SHARP HealthCare - San Diego, CA

Programmer Analyst

- Developed extensive batch programs for SHARP and outside clients.
- Aided and educated other senior system analysts on how to develop an optimal SQL query while developing them as well.
- Enhanced and optimized on old web interfaces on Lawson for efficiency.
- Programming Languages and tools used: Oracle & DB2 SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, COBOL, Remedy, Fiddler, Lawson, Infor ProcessFlow Automation (IPA)

Corelation Inc. - San Diego, CA

September 2016 - September 2017

Software Developer I

- Developed and performed revision, repair or expansion for over 50 programs to increase operating efficiency.
- Collaborated closely with team members to plan, design, and develop robust solutions for internal tools.
- Programming Languages and tools used: DB2 SQL, Java, XML, NetBeans, JUnit Testing, IBM Data Studio, JIRA, Git & GitBash.

High Tech High Media Arts -- San Diego, CA **High School Tutor/Mentor Intern**

April 2015 - June 2015

October 2017 - Present

- Aided more than half of a classroom who were new to computer coding and also helped those who were experienced reinforce their programming knowledge and art fundamentals.
- Programming Language and tools used: Processing

PROJECTS

COBRA Interface April 2018 - Present

- COBOL Interface that sends COBRA-eligible terminated employees' data to WageWorks.
- A two part interface that first, stores the data in a custom table and then creates a CSV extract to be sent to the vendor.

Lawson Printer Process Flow

January 2019 - February 2019

- A process flow interface that finds all the offline Lawson printers across SHARP and brings them back online.
- Redeveloped initial process flow to include a count, an attempt to 'up' the printer, and an email sent to the department.

Mass Adobe PDF Upload

July 2017 - September 2017

- A script utilizing Java and SQL that mass uploads PDF forms to the core system.
- Program parses through an excel sheet with data, searches for files, and applies specified settings when uploading.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science & Engineering

September 2016

University of California, San Diego - San Diego, CA